<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>undefined-thought</title>
    <link href="https://marco-fp.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://marco-fp.github.io/blog" />
    <updated>2017-08-15T00:13:07+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Marco Fernandez Pranno</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://marco-fp.github.io/blog</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Getting started with React Native</title>
        <author>
            <name>Marco Fernandez Pranno</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://marco-fp.github.io/blog/how-to-setup-react-native.html"/>
        <id>https://marco-fp.github.io/blog/how-to-setup-react-native.html</id>
            <category term="react-native"/>
            <category term="how-to"/>

        <updated>2017-08-15T00:13:02+02:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>React Native lets you create mobile applications using the same design as React, with javascript. The result is a native mobile application, identical to one written in Objective-C or Java.&nbsp;</p>
<p>To accomplish this, React Native renders components that translate into native implementations.</p>
<p>In addition, we'll be able to re-use native code whenever we need to, as easily as importing the file and rendering it as a component in our React Native view.<br><br></p>
<hr>
<p>To speed things up, we'll be using&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/react-community/create-react-native-app">create-react-native-app</a>, a library that will let us build an application without any configuration.&nbsp;</p>
<p>(Of course, we could set things up manually, but the configuration of things like hot-reloading and optimized builds is out of the scope of this post)</p>
<p>To complete this quick guide you'll an Android device and computer with an OS capable of running Node and NPM, connected to the same private network (WLAN/LAN).</p>
<p>Asuming we already have NPM and Node 6.x installed, follow this steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Install <em>create-react-native-app</em> globally
<blockquote>$&gt; npm install -g create-react-native-app</blockquote>
<br><img class="post__image--wide" src="https://marco-fp.github.io/blog/media/posts/1/photo_2017-08-15_00-09-53.jpg" alt="" width="1280" height="244"></li>
<li>Initialize and setup the foundation of our first application<br>
<blockquote>$&gt; create-react-native-app my-first-app</blockquote>
<br><img class="post__image--full" src="https://marco-fp.github.io/blog/media/posts/1/photo_2017-08-15_00-09-43.jpg" alt="" width="1280" height="590"><br><br><img class="post__image--wide" src="https://marco-fp.github.io/blog/media/posts/1/photo_2017-08-14_23-54-50.jpg" alt="" width="1068" height="1026"><br><br></li>
<li>Step into the project's directory and run the project
<blockquote>$&gt; cd my-first-app/<br>$&gt; yarnpkg start</blockquote>
<br><img class="post__image--wide" src="https://marco-fp.github.io/blog/media/posts/1/photo_2017-08-15_00-10-39.jpg" alt="" width="941" height="1280"></li>
</ol>
<p>At this point we'll have our application initialized and running and a QR code will be displayed on the terminal.</p>
<p>It's time to switch to our Android devise, and install&nbsp;<a href="https://expo.io/">Expo</a>. This application will allow us to scan the QR code and synchronize our development environment with the devise.</p>
<p>Our application will load and render on the device, while we can enable a debugging tool to open on a browser in the computer.</p>
<p>Since we have hot-reloading out of the box, making a change on our project's files will automatically result in a change on the devise.<br><br></p>
<hr>
<p>If you found this guide useful or have any suggestion, please feel free to share it in the comments.</p>
<p>Happy hacking!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
